<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USDA Forest Service</origin>
        <pubdate>20221107</pubdate>
        <title> RAVG Initial assessment of the 2022 MOSQUITO fire (Event ID CA3900612074520220907)</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/ravg/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The RAVG (Rapid Assessment of Vegetation Condition after Wildfire) program provides assessments of vegetation conditions following large fires on forested lands. Fire effects are represented by three metrics: percent change in live basal area (BA), percent change in canopy cover (CC), and the standardized Composite Burn Index (CBI). These data are derived from moderate resolution multi-spectral imagery (e.g., Landsat 8 Operational Land Imager or Sentinel-2 Multispectral Instrument). The Relative Differenced Normalized Burn Ratio (RdNBR), which is correlated to the variation of burn severity within a fire, is calculated from a pair of images (pre- and postfire), judiciously selected to capture fire effects. The three severity metrics are in turn calculated from RdNBR using regression equations developed from and calibrated with historical field data.</abstract>
      <purpose>RAVG data are generated for wildland fires on forested National Forest System (NFS) lands by the USDA Forest Service Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC) to support Washington Office Forest Management staff; Regional, Forest and District silviculturists; and other Forest Service personnel and programs involved in reforestation, restoration or related efforts. In addition, GTAC and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS) Center support other Federal and State land management agencies on a by-request basis within then-current resource constraints.</purpose>
      <supplinf><![CDATA[
      Fire Information 
        Event ID: CA3900612074520220907
        Fire Name: MOSQUITO
        Date of Fire: 2022-09-07
        Agency: USDA Forest Service
        Land Management Unit: Tahoe National Forest
        Type of Assessment: Initial 
        Acres within Fire Perimeter (as mapped): 76821

        Pre-Fire Sensor, Date, Scene ID: Landsat 9 OLI-2, 2022-09-01, 904303320220901 
        Post-Fire Sensor, Date, Scene ID: Landsat 8 OLI, 2022-09-25, 804303320220925 
      
        Analyst comments for this dataset: 1. This assessment is based on imagery acquired will before the expected containment date of 1 November; however, there is very little active fire visible and the differences visible within the perimeter over the following month appear to be almost entirely due to increasing terrain shadows. Later imagery is less desirable due to the increasing terrain shadows. 2. There are many small patches with little to no pre-fire tree cover visible in the pre-fire imagery. In these areas, the modeled values are less reliable since the observed reflectance is strongly dominated by the non-tree component.
        
      Naming convention
        Filenames are in one of the following forms:
          <event_id>_<prefire_image_date>_<product>,
          <event_id>_<postfire_image_date>_<product>, or
          <event_id>_<prefire_image_date>_<postfire_image_date>_<product>.
          
        The event ID is formed from the fire ignition location and start date: the two letter state abbreviation, the latitude and longitude (decimal degrees to three decimal places), and the start date (formatted as YYYYMMDD). The image dates identify the date of acquisition (year, month, day). The product identifies the data content, as described below.
      
      Product List:
      
        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_L9_refl.tif
          Prefire top-of-atmosphere reflectance, clipped to the vicinity of the burn boundary, rescaled and converted to integer. Sensor: Landsat 9 OLI-2. Band order (1-8): B, G, R, NIR, SWIR-1, SWIR-2, Coastal Blue, Cirrus. For best viewing set RGB to bands 7, 5, 3. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. 

        ca3900612074520220907_20220925_L8_refl.tif
          Postfire top-of-atmosphere reflectance clipped to the vicinity of the burn boundary, rescaled and converted to integer. Sensor: Landsat 8 OLI. Band order (1-8): B, G, R, NIR, SWIR-1, SWIR-2, Coastal Blue, Cirrus. For best viewing set RGB to bands 7, 5, 3. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. 

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_dnbr.tif
          Absolute differenced normalized burn ratio (dnbr). File type: signed 16-bit GeoTIFF.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr.tif
          Relative differenced normalized burn ratio (Rdnbr). File type: signed 16-bit GeoTIFF.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_ba.tif
          Continuous scaled percent change (mortality) in basal area (0 - 100%), derived from Rdnbr. Unmappable areas identified as -9999. File type: real-valued GeoTIFF.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_cc.tif
          Continuous scaled percent change (mortality) in canopy cover (0 - 100%), derived from Rdnbr. Unmappable areas identified as -9999. File type: real-valued GeoTIFF.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_cbi.tif
          Continuous scaled severity in composite burn index (CBI) units (0 - 3), derived from Rdnbr. The CBI vegetation severity rating is based upon a composite of the severity to the understory vegetation (grass, shrub layers), midstory trees and overstory trees. Unmappable areas identified as -9999. File type: real-valued GeoTIFF.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_ba4.tif
          Four-category percent basal area (BA) mortality, clipped to fire perimeter. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. Classes:
            0 = outside perimeter
            1 = 0% BA mortality
            2 = 0%  <  BA mortality < 25%
            3 = 25% <= BA mortality < 75%
            4 = BA mortality >= 75%
            9 = unmappable

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_ba7.tif
          Seven-category percent basal area (BA) mortality, clipped to fire perimeter. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. Classes:
            0 = outside perimeter
            1 = 0% BA mortality
            2 =  0% <  BA mortality < 10%
            3 = 10% <= BA mortality < 25%
            4 = 25% <= BA mortality < 50%
            5 = 50% <= BA mortality < 75%
            6 = 75% <= BA mortality < 90%
            7 = BA mortality >= 90%
            9 = unmappable

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_cc5.tif
          Five-category percent canopy cover (CC) mortality clipped to fire perimeter. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. Classes:
            0 = outside perimeter
            1 = 0% CC mortality
            2 = 0%  <  CC mortality < 25%
            3 = 25% <= CC mortality < 50%
            4 = 50% <= CC mortality < 75%
            5 = CC mortality >= 75%
            9 = unmappable

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_rdnbr_cbi4.tif
          Four-category severity classification based on CBI, clipped to fire perimeter. File type: unsigned 8-bit GeoTIFF. Classes:
            0 = outside perimeter
            1 = unchanged         (0    <= CBI <  0.1)
            2 = low severity      (0.1  <= CBI <  1.25)
            3 = moderate severity (1.25 <= CBI <  2.25)
            4 = high severity     (2.25 <= CBI <= 3.0)
            9 = unmappable

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_burn_bndy.shp
          Fire perimeter delineated from the postfire image and dnbr or Rdnbr. The most current incident perimeter from the National Interagency Fire Center (NIFC) is typically used as an initial perimeter and edited, if needed, to match the burned area boundary visible in the image data. File type: Esri shapefile.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_mask.shp
          Vector mask for clouds, shadow, water, snow, active fire, smoke, or other anomalies intersecting the fire area, delineated from pre- and postfire imagery. Included only if not empty. File type: Esri shapefile.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_table_ba.xlsx
          Tabular summary of area (acres) within fire perimeter, summarized by RAVG vegetation class, land ownership and wilderness status, and basal area (BA) loss class. Also includes class definitions (vegetation, land ownership/status, and BA loss). File type: Microsoft Excel document.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_table_cc.xlsx
          Tabular summary of area (acres) within fire perimeter, summarized by RAVG vegetation class, land ownership and wilderness status, and canopy cover (CC) loss class. Also includes class definitions (vegetation, land ownership/status, and CC loss). File type: Microsoft Excel document.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_table_cbi.xlsx
          Tabular summary of area (acres) within fire perimeter, summarized by RAVG vegetation class, land ownership and wilderness status, and composite burn index (CBI) class. Also includes class definitions (vegetation, land ownership/status, and CBI). File type: Microsoft Excel document.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_map_ba.pdf
          Map product showing postfire imagery (RGB = SWIR, NIR, Red) overlaid with the burned area boundary (first panel), and a modified 4-class basal area loss superimposed on a topographic layer (second panel). File type: PDF document.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_map_cc.pdf
          Map product showing postfire imagery (RGB = SWIR, NIR, Red) overlaid with the burned area boundary (first panel), and the 5-class canopy cover loss superimposed on a topographic layer (second panel). File type: PDF document.

        ca3900612074520220907_20220901_20220925_ravg_map_cbi.pdf
          Map product showing postfire imagery (RGB = SWIR, NIR, Red) overlaid with the burned area boundary (first panel), and the 4-class composite burn index (CBI) superimposed on a topographic layer (second panel). File type: PDF document.

      For additional information:
        See https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/ravg/ for project information and data access.
        See https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/ravg/contact for questions or additional support.
        See https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/ravg/reference for descriptions of the analysis underlying RAVG processes and data.
      ]]>
      </supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2022-09-07</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <descgeog>RAVG burn measures</descgeog>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-120.8458152991233</westbc>
        <eastbc>-120.53700196955016</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.17848033038358</northbc>
        <southbc>38.904661040337764</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Wildfire</themekey>
        <themekey>Wildland fire</themekey>
        <themekey>RAVG</themekey>
        <themekey>Landsat</themekey>
        <themekey>Sentinel-2</themekey>
        <themekey>Normalized burn ratio</themekey>
        <themekey>Relative differenced normalized burn ratio</themekey>
        <themekey>Burned area</themekey>
        <themekey>Burn severity</themekey>
        <themekey>Fire location</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>Continental U.S.</placekey>
        <placekey>Alaska</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
        <placekey>CONUS</placekey>
        <placekey>AK</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>There are no restrictions on use, except for reasonable and proper acknowledgement of information sources.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA Forest Service Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC), Disturbance Assessment and Services (DAS) Program</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>RAVG Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>125 South State Street, Suite 7105</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>UT</state>
          <postal>84138</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-975-3800</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>SM.FS.PostFireRAVG@usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>USDA Forest Service; USGS</datacred>
    <native>ERDAS Imagine, and Esri ArcGIS</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>RAVG analysts seek to optimize the quality and consistency of RAVG data products by selecting imagery pairs that most accurately capture fire effects on vegetation within the burned area while minimizing changes due to other effects (e.g., clouds, snow and other obstruction within the burned area, and seasonal/phenological differences in the vicinity of the burned area).</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>No tests for logical consistency have been performed on this map layer.</logic>
    <complete>Data completeness reflects the state of the fire (active or extinguished) and the availability of suitable imagery (including Landsat and Sentinel-2 multispectral imagery).</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Each Landsat image used to create the burn severity measures, was precision terrain-corrected using 3-arc-second digital terrain elevation data, and georegistered using ground control points resulting in a root mean square registration error of less than 1 pixel (30 meters). Sentinel-2 images are believed to have similar accuracy.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>N/A</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc> RAVG data creation:
        
        RAVG data products are derived from moderate-resolution multi-spectral imagery (primarily from the Landsat and Sentinel-2 platforms). Typically, only imagery that has been terrain corrected and geometrically rectified are used. The following process description is based on Landsat imagery (L5 TM, L7 ETM+ and L8 OLI) but the principles apply to other multi-spectral imagery that has bands in the near-infrared (NIR) and short-wave infrared (SWIR, near 2.2 micrometers).

        Selected pre- and postfire images are processed to convert relevant bands to at-sensor reflectance and the Normalized Burn Ratio (NBR) is computed from the NIR and SWIR bands:

            NBR = (NIR - SWIR) / (NIR + SWIR)

        The Differenced NBR (dNBR) is computed as the difference between pre- and postfire NBR:

            dNBR = (PreNBR - PostNBR)*1000

        dNBR is scaled by 1000 in the equation above to facilitate representation in integer format. The Relative dNBR is computed by applying an offset and scale factor to the dNBR:

            RdNBR = (dNBR - Offset)/sqrt(abs(PreNBR/1000))

        Higher RdNBR values are correlated with more severe fire effects. The scale factor in the denominator of the RdNBR equation is intended to reduce correlation with pre-fire vegetation density. The offset is applied to account for seasonal or interannual differences between the two images. It is calculated as the average dNBR for unburned areas in the vicinity of the fire having vegetation cover similar to that of the burned area.  

        Regression models for three continuous burn severity measures (Composite Burn Index (CBI), percent basal area mortality (BA loss) and percent canopy cover mortality (CC loss)) were developed from imagery-based RdNBR data and field data collected one year postfire. Field data included CBI, which is a field-based composite of fire effects on the field plot as a whole across five vertical strata (forest floor through upper canopy), and individual tree data (species, diameter (dbh), height, status (live or dead) and observed fire effects metrics). Live basal area was calculated from measured dbh, with the pre-fire BA including trees that were believed to have been alive before (and killed by) the fire. Canopy cover was estimated using the Forest Vegetation Simulator with species and dbh for live trees as input. Finally, RdNBR was determined for each field plot from Landsat TM or ETM+ data. Postfire imagery was selected from the summer of the year following the fire to roughly match the field sampling date. Prefire imagery was selected from the same time of year as the postfire imagery in order to minimize seasonal effects. (For more details, see Miller et al. 2009, "Calibration and validation of the relative differenced Normalized Burn Ratio (RdNBR) to three measures of fire severity in the Sierra Nevada and Klamath Mountains, California, USA", Remote Sensing of Environment 113: 645-656.)

        The resulting models are shown below: 

            CBI = (1/0.389)*LN((RdNBR + 369.0)/421.7)
            %BA_loss = 100*(SIN((RdNBR - 166.5)/389.0))^2
            %CC_loss = 100*(SIN((RdNBR - 161.0)/392.6))^2

        These models are used for "extended assessments"; that is, assessments based on postfire imagery acquired near the peak of green following the growing season after the fire.

        For "initial assessments" (where the postfire imagery is acquired within a few weeks after fire containment), the following equations apply:

            CBI = (1/0.389)*LN((RdNBR/1.144 + 369.0)/421.7)
            %BA_loss = 100*(SIN((RdNBR/1.144 - 166.5)/389.0))^2
            %CC_loss = 100*(SIN((RdNBR/1.144 - 161.0)/392.6))^2
        
        The adjustment for initial assessments was derived through regression modeling of satellite reflectance values from imagery collected one year postfire to imagery acquired immediately postfire. (For more details, see Miller and Quayle 2015, "Calibration and validation of immediate post-fire satellite-derived data to three severity metrics", Fire Ecology 11(2):12-30.)
        
        Continuous CBI data are reclassified into four severity classes representing the following conditions:

            Unchanged - Conditions one year after the fire were indistinguishable from prefire conditions. This does not always indicate the area did not burn.

            Low - Surface fire with little change in cover and little mortality of the structurally dominant vegetation.

            Moderate - Severity class between low and high, with a mixture of effects on the structurally dominant vegetation.

            High - High to complete mortality observed in the dominant vegetation.

        The field-collected CBI data were used to calibrate the regression model. Values of 0.1, 1.25, and 2.25 were chosen to correspond to the low, moderate and high thresholds, respectively.
        
        The regression models are applied to the whole fire extent. Errors in modeled values may result from several factors including delayed mortality, resprouting, and non-tree vegetation.</procdesc>
      <procdate>20221107</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Data Distribution: RAVG data are accessible through the program website (https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/ravg/data-access), which allows users to download datasets for individual fires or explore query-based data summaries. The site has links to other sites where the data are available in other formats, including annual mosaics and map services.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20221107</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
      <rowcount>1033.8</rowcount>
      <colcount>873.6</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.5</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.5</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.0</latprjo>
            <feast>0</feast>
            <fnorth>0</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30</absres>
            <ordres>30</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983 (NAD 83)</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.2572221010042</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Fire perimeter shapefile</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Producer Defined</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Event_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Event ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>The Event-ID is generated by combining several attributes taken from the fire ignition location and start date. The Event-ID is constructed from the two letter state abbreviation, the decimal degree latitude and longitude, both carried to the third decimal place without the decimal point (if less than 100 degrees the longitude is padded with a leading '0'), and the start date formatted as YYYYMMDD (e.g., TX2672909780020110102).</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>irwinID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>IRWIN ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IRWIN Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>The IRWIN ID is a unique identifier created by the Integrated Reporting of Wildland-Fire Information (IRWIN) service. Example: 5DF6471C-07B0-4EA0-8188-4F83B18A47F8</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Incid_Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of fire (UNNAMED if not identifiable from source fire occurrence databases).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
        <udom>Example: Tank Hollow</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Incid_Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Documented type of fire (WF: Wildfire, Rx: Prescribed Fire; UNK:Unknown).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Wildfire</edomv>
            <edomvd>An unplanned, unwanted wildland fire including unauthorized human-caused fires, escaped wildland fire use events, escaped prescribed fire projects, and all other wildland fires where the objective is to put the fire out.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Prescribed fire</edomv>
            <edomvd>Any fire intentionally ignited by management actions in accordance with applicable laws, policies, and regulations to meet specific objectives.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Wildland fire use</edomv>
            <edomvd>An event dealing with the management of a naturally ignited wildland fire to accomplish specific prestated resource management objectives in predefined geographic areas outlined in the Fire Management Plans.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Unknown</edomv>
            <edomvd>A fire event whose incident type was not reported from the original reporting agency.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Out of area response</edomv>
            <edomvd>Multiple resource response to a wildfire incident. This term applies exclusively to wildfire incidents.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Complex</edomv>
            <edomvd>Two or more individual incidents located in the same general area which are assigned to a single incident commander or unified command.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mapping ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>99999999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_Prog</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mapping program/protocol the fire was mapped with.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Examples: MTBS, RAVG, BAER, NPS</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Asmnt_Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fire mapping assessment label (Initial (SS) (SS=single scene), Initial, Extended, Extended (SS) (SS=single scene), Emergency, or Emergency (SS)).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Initial</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired shortly after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Initial (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired shortly after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Extended</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during seasonal peak-of-green after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Extended (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during seasonal peak-of-green after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during active incident or immediatly after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during active incident or immediatly after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndAc</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Number of acres mapped.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>None</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndLat</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude of the mapped centroid of fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>17.957</rdommin>
            <rdommax>70.139</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndLon</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude of the mapped centroid of fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-165.881</rdommin>
            <rdommax>-65.35</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Ig_Date</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date of fire ignition (from source fire occurrence databases).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Example: 9/30/1992</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Pre_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel pre scene ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Example: 503803520040723</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Post_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel post scene ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Example: 701503620081007</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Perim_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel perimeter scene ID. Used to help delineate perimeter. Not always present.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Example: A15RVQ20190514</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>dNBR_offst</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The mean dNBR value sampled from an unburned area outside the fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>dNBR_stdDv</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The standard deviation of the mean dNBR value sampled from an unburned area outside the fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Comment</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>As needed comments or notes provided by the mapping analyst to the end user.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>125 South State Street, Suite 7105</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>UT</state>
          <postal>84138</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-975-3800</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>SM.FS.PostFireRAVG@usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>This product is produced from geospatial information prepared by the U.S. Geological Survey EROS and USDA Forest Service. By taking receipt of these files via electronic file transfer methods, you understand that the data may be updated due to the availability of additional data or revision of existing data. Represented features may not be in an accurate geographic location. Neither the USDA Forest Service, GTAC, the U.S. Geological Survey nor EROS make any express or implied warranty, including warranty of merchantability and fitness, with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the data or their appropriateness for any user's purposes. The USDA Forest Service and the U.S. Geological Survey reserve the right to correct, update, modify, or replace this geospatial information without notification.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform><digtinfo>
          <formname>Digital Data</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/P9IED7RZ</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20221107</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>RAVG Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>125 South State Street, Suite 7105</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>UT</state>
          <postal>84138</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-975-3800</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>SM.FS.PostFireRAVG@usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Biological Data Profile of the Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001.1-1999</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
